Guide to the Ruth Asawa Papers M1585
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4. Art
  - 4.6 exhibition announcements and catalogs
    Contains catalogs, cards, posters, and fliers for Asawa exhibitions and events. The majority are from museums and galleries, including solo and group show notices from Peridot Gallery, the Tin Angel (with Jean Varda), the San Francisco Museum of Art/Museum of Modern Art, the M.H. de Young Memorial Museum, and the San Francisco Art Commission Gallery (then known as Capricorn Asunder). Some bear notes or addresses. Also filed here are publications related to her public sculpture projects including the Hyatt Fountain, Parc 55 frieze, and Nihonmachi Fountains, as well as auction catalogs from Christie's and Bonhams.
    - 1950-1954 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - III Biennial, Sao Paulo catalog, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - 1959 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - 1982 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - 1992-1994 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - 1995 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - 2003-2005 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Contours in the Air, de Young, 2006-2007 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - 2006-2009 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - 2010-2013 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - oversize items
      - original pencil drawing for Shop One exhibition, Rochester, New York, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - "An Afternoon With Asawa" Kinokuniya Bookstore, Buchanan YMCA Benefit, 1969-06-01 (Flat-box 78, Folder 8)
        Illustration by McDonnell and Masursky, printed by SF Arts Commission Neighborhood Arts Program.
      - "Images of Bay Area Artists" SF MOMA October 13-November 21, 1976 poster by Mimi Jacobs, with enclosed note (Map-folder 56)
      - Oakland Museum: 100 Years of California Sculpture [exhibition catalog], 1982 (Flat-box 78, Folder 5)
      - miscellaneous exhibition and event posters (Flat-box 193, Folder 4)
        Some posters are publicity for events not involving Asawa but use her art.
  - 4.7 exhibition photographs
    Also contains floor plans, media, etc.
    - Albert's Design for Laverne Showroom, circa 1951 (Flat-box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Four Artist-Craftsmen" show, San Francisco Museum of Art, April 1-May 2, 1954 (Box 215, Folder 5)
      Show featured Marguerite Wildenhain, pottery; Merry Renk, jewelry; Ruth Asawa, sculpture; and Ida Dean [Grae], weaving. The installation was designed by Albert Lanier.
    - SF Museum of Art floorplan [for "Four Artist-Craftsmen" show], 1954 (Map-folder 56)
    - Peridot Gallery, 1954 (Box 215, Folder 6)
      Possibly the opening of the show. Most people in photos are identified as Ruth's friends from Black Mountain College, including Bobbie Dreier, Anne Fuller, Joan Stack, John Urbain, Wade Williams, Peggy Bennett Cole, William Cole, Pete Jennerjahn, Richard Lippold, and Ray Johnson (from behind only). Multiple prints.
    - Peridot Gallery, 1958 (Box 215, Folder 7)
    - de Young Museum, 1960 (Flat-box 241, Folder 7, Box 215, Folder 8)
    - Kinokuniya Bookstore exhibit, 1960s (Box 215, Folder 9)
    - Capper Gallery, 1969 (Box 215, Folder 10, Flat-box 241, Folder 8)
      Opening of show, with Asawa and Imogen Cunningham.
    - "Retrospective View" show, San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1973 (Box 216, Folder 1)
    - Van Doren Gallery, 1973 (Box 216, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Art Commission Honor Award Exhibition, Art Commission Gallery (slides), 1976 (Box 216, Folder 2)
    - Los Robles Gallery, Palo Alto, 1986 (Box 216, Folder 3)
    - "In the Advent of Change, 1945-1969" show, Fresno Arts Center, 1986 (Box 216, Folder 4)
    - Euphrat Gallery, 1989 (Box 216, Folder 5)
    - Strength And Diversity show, Oakland Museum, 1990 (Box 216, Folder 5)
    - Open Studio, 1116 Castro (Box 216, Folder 15)
    - "With New Eyes: Toward an Asian-American Art History in the United States" show, SFSU Art Department Gallery, 1995-1996 (Box 216, Folder 6)
    - "Leading The Way" show, 2001 (Box 216, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Museum of Art "Vital Forms" Introduction [video], 2001; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      "Vital Forms: American Art and Design in the Atomic Age 1940-1960" exhibition promotional video. Asawa speaks at 6:13, Imogen Cunningham photograph of Asawa at 7:10, Gordon Onslow Ford at 3:22.
    - "Completing the Circle" show, Fresno Art Museum, 2001 (Box 216, Folder 8)
    - "Completing the Circle" show, Oakland Museum, 2002 (Flat-box 241, Folder 9, Box 216)
    - Tobey C. Moss Gallery, 2003 (Box 216, Folder 10)
    - de Young Museum opening photographs by Scott Wall [contact sheets], 2006-11 (Flat-box 78, Folder 7)
    - de Young Museum floorplan, including tower with permanent installation of wire sculptures, 2005-2006 (Map-folder 194)
    - "Contours In The Air" retrospective show, de Young, 2006 (Box 216, Folder 11)
    - Christies Private Sales Gallery, 2013-05 (Box 216, Folder 12)
    - miscellaneous slides, 1962-1979 (Box 216, Folder 13)
      Includes Ankrum Gallery, SF Art Festival, Fresno Art Center 1978-79, Cabrillo College, Cedar Street Gallery, etc.
    - miscellaneous slides, 1982-2002 (Box 216, Folder 14)
      Includes Fibreworks 1982, MOCA "Blueprints for Modern Living" 1989-1990, J.J. Brookings Gallery 1996, "Parallels and Intersections: Art/Women/California" show at San Jose Museum of Art 2002, etc.
- Series 5. Correspondence, Artists and Colleagues, 1948-2009
  Please note that there are articles, exhibition announcements, and other material in addition to correspondence here, and that no correspondence is present for some individuals. The vast majority of letters are incoming, and some address Albert or the Lanier family. This series shares some material with personal and professional correspondence, Black Mountain College, and other series.
  - Mark Adams (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Stanford University holds the Mark Adams papers (M1747): http://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/8610212
    Textile artist, Ruth referred him for some commissions. See also wife Beth Van Hoesen (cards from both are filed there).
    Adams, Mark
  - Josef and Anni Albers
    Correspondence with and printed materials concerning artist, color theorist, designer, and teacher Josef Albers and his wife Anni Albers, herself a textile artist and jeweler. The Albers were refugee scholars from Germany who taught at Black Mountain College for sixteen years, and are perhaps its most referenced faculty in a sea of famous names. He had both studied and taught at the Bauhaus; Anni had also been a student teacher. Their presence in the rural mountains of North Carolina set many on a new path.
    Ruth Asawa took Josef Albers' classes at Black Mountain repeatedly, beginning with the arts-intensive Summer session in 1946. He was initially put off by her messiness (he would not visit her studio until she cleaned it), but their rapport became quite strong, and we can owe much of Ruth's approach to art-making to him in particular.
    After Black Mountain, Josef Albers remained eager to assist his former student, and there are referrals from him in her applications for scholarships, fellowships, and further academic study. It is in her 1950 San Francisco State recommendation that Albers famously stated "I consider her as a most gifted art student and one of the most talented I have ever had." She in turn frequently credited Albers in interviews, lectured on him at the San Francisco Museum of Art, and the Laniers traveled to Europe for the opening of the Albers museum in Bottrup. They also traded art many times over the years.
    Files include letters and notes to and from the Albers, holiday and other cards, prints (some inscribed), photographs, and published material such as catalogs, books, magazines, and articles. Some of the correspondence has been copied from the Albers Foundation, which overlaps in part with original drafts present here. See also Black Mountain files, Ruth's BMC class notes, and the Fellowships and Grants series.
    Albers, Anni; Albers, Josef; Albers, Anni; Albers, Josef
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes photograph of Albers probably at Black Mountain College, attributed to Ted [Dreier] Jr., as well as notes and cards from the Albers, etc.
    - 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 2001-2010 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - articles and publications (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - snapshots of Albers show at Guggenheim (Box 218, Folder 3)
    - Josef Albers. Homage to the Square. Produced by Museum At Large [video], 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Josef Albers documentary featuring Robert Rauschenberg and Richard Anuszkiewicz. Produced and directed by Hans Namuth and Paul Faulkenberg. A Chelsea House Publishers Production for University-at-Large Programs.
  - Irene Poon Anderson (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Art historian, included Ruth in her "Leading the Way" book and exhibition. Mostly holidays cards from Irene and her husband Stan.
    Poon, Irene
  - Elaine Badgely Arnoux (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Drew portrait of Asawa in "People of San Francisco" book.
  - Mai Arbegast (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Landscape architect specializing in garden design. Worked with Ruth on many projects, including Bayside Plaza and Mission Viejo Mall.
    UC Berkeley's Environmental Design Archives holds the Mai Kitazawa Arbegast Collection: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4v19r98p.
    Arbegast, Mai
  - Lisa Jalowetz Aronson (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Daughter of Black Mountain College Music teacher Heinrich "Jalo" Jalowetz and his wife Johanna (often referred to as "Mrs.Jalo"). Her sister was Trude Guermonprez; both Trude and Johanna relocated to Northern California after BMC. Lisa later married theatrical set designer Boris Aronson. See also BMC correspondence.
    Aronson, Lisa Jalowetz
  - Kazuko Asaba (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Japanese children's art advocate and cultural ambassador, produced "Kids Paradise IV: An Exhibition of Children’s Art from the West Coast of the U.S.A." with Asawa and others in 1988.
    Asaba, Kazuko
  - Raymond Barnhart (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Sculptor who was part of the Black Mountain contingent in Northern California.
    Barnhart, Raymond
  - Maggie Baylis and Doug Baylis (Box 13, Folder 8)
    UC Berkeley's Environmental Design Archives holds the Douglas and Maggie Baylis Collection: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt2k4004jk
    Douglas Baylis was a landscape architect and San Francisco Art Commissioner who helped design Civic Center Plaza. His wife was a graphic designer who collaborated with him on articles; most correspondence is from her (he passed away in 1971).
    Baylis, Douglas; Baylis, Maggie
  - Elio Benvenuto (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Artist, served on the San Francisco Art Commission with Ruth. See also Art Commission files.
    Benvenuto, Elio
  - Mary Phelan Outten Bowles (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Black Mountain alumnus, later she and Ruth would paint together while their children had play dates. See also BMC files.
    Bowles, Mary Phelan
  - Alan Brooks (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Black Mountain alumnus, taught art at City College, collaborated with Ruth on projects.
    Brooks, Alan
  - Michael D. Brown (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Collector of Japanese art, introduced himself to Ruth by writing "Please call me. Arthur Okamura and Hisako Hibi have been trying to get me to see you."
    Brown, Michael D. (Michael Donald)
  - Brio Burgess (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Author, musician, mutual friend of Peggy Tolk-Watkins.
    Burgess, Brio
  - A-B (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Joan Abrahamson; Masha Archer; Olive Ayhens; Jeanne Babette; Eric Barnes; Mark Baugh; Mary and Alfred Baxter; Fletcher Benton; Al Benson; Fred Berman (MSTC student); David Best; Susan Hooper Billstein (CAC executive director); Bernice Bing; Lucienne Bloch; Bill Bondy; Esther and Ernest Born; Morris Broderson; Leo Burnett
  - John Cage (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Articles only, no correspondence.
    Cage, John
  - Remy Charlip (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Dancer, author. Performed with Merce Cunningham at Black Mountain. Moved to San Francisco much later, worked with Ruth.
    Charlip, Remy
  - Perci Chester (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Sculptor, Alvarado artist-in-residence.
    Chester, Perci
  - Chester Comstock (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Metalworker, did casting for Ruth at foundry.
    Comstock, Chester
  - Imogen Cunningham
    Unlike many of their artist friends, the Laniers did not meet Imogen Cunningham through Black Mountain College, but indirectly through Albert's job. In 1950 Albert worked for architect Mario Corbett, and Imogen's son Ronderly had been assigned to photograph Corbett's house down the peninsula in Redwood City. Albert assisted Ron with mounting the photos, and on the way home he told Albert about his mother. Coincidentally, Imogen lived only a few blocks away from their apartment on Russian Hill, and not long after she paid them a visit bearing a jar of Satsuma plum jam.
    Subsequently, they became fast friends and a source of mutual artistic support. Ruth, and her family, friends, and art were subjects of many photographs by Imogen. She invited Ruth to join the San Francisco Women Artists, where she met Hisako Hibi, Emmy Lou Packard, Beth Van Hoesen, and others. Imogen also supplied photographs for Ruth's portfolios and fellowship applications. She convinced Ruth to use her maiden name professionally, and tried to discourage her from having more children. Imogen was also critical of Ruth's work in schools and thought it was a waste of time compared to her own art. Nevertheless, she did contribute to Ruth's dough fountain along with many school children, and participated in its opening ceremonies.
    Imogen's friendship with Albert Lanier shouldn't be overlooked. Early on, Albert did a lot of carpentry and odd jobs for her, and an interest in gardening and botany further bonded them. They also shared birthdays with an annual party in Golden Gate Park.
    Files also contain a great deal of Friends of Imogen Cunningham and Imogen Cunningham Trust correspondence and other material.
    Cunningham, Imogen; Cunningham, Imogen
    - 1951-1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Friends of Imogen Cunningham, 1976-1983 (Box 7, Folders 1-3)
    - Partridges, 1954-2010 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - articles and publications (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - photographs (Box 218, Folder 4)
      Includes photos from from birthday celebrations at Golden Gate Park, dining with the Laniers and Devadases by Rajan Devadas (Ruth's brother-in-law) in 1965 and with Ruth at the Hyatt opening in 1973.
    - photographs, Asawas and Laniers by Cunningham (Box 218, Folder 5)
    - photographs, oversize (Flat-box 241, Folder 6)
    - Friends of Imogen Cunningham Valentines Day Attendance roster (Map-folder 56)
    - Imogen. Produced By The Kitchen Sisters For National Public Radio [audio], 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 14)
      radio program about Cunningham, produced by The Kitchen Sisters (Nikki Silva and Davia Nelson). Ruth is quoted.
  - Julia Connor (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Poet, protege of M.C. Richards.
    Connor, Julia
  - Merce Cunningham (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Cunningham, Merce
  - Merry Renk Curtis and Earle Curtis (Box 14, Folder 8)
    The Curtises were very close friends with Ruth and Albert. Merry Renk was a jewelsmith and artist, Earle Curtis was a potter and ceramicist. Although they shared a duplex with the Laniers in the early 1950s, they may have known each other before. Both were Alvarado artists-in-residence and worked creatively with Ruth. Renk exhibited with her in the "Four Artist-Craftsmen" show at the Museum of Art in 1954.
    The Smithsonian Archives of American Art holds the Merry Renk papers: http://www.aaa.si.edu/collections/merry-renk-papers-6039
    Renk, Merry; Curtis, Earle
  - C (Box 177, Folder 1)
    Herb Caen; Charles and Glenna Campbell; Kit Cameron; Art Carpenter; Lynn Carruthers-Dupell; Kaleo and Elise Ching; Benjamin Chinn; Lenore Chinn; Lu Churchill; Carmen Cicero; Judith Clancy (Johns); Trudy Clawson; Gordon Cook; Mariana Cook; Charles Counts; Marilyn Coyote; Peter Coyote; Mitzi Cunliffe; Gabrielle Curry
  - Jacques D'Amboise
    See also D'Amboise material in School of the Arts series.
    Dancer and teacher, taught several workshops at the School of the Arts.
    D'Amboise, Jacques; D'Amboise, Jacques
    - correspondence, clippings etc. (Box 177, Folder 2)
      D'Amboise, Jacques
    - Jacques D'Amboise John F. Kennedy Presidential Award [video], 1995; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 47, Folder 18)
      Off-air recording of 18th annual Kennedy Center Honors, D'Amboise one of several recipients, includes his segment only.
    - Jacques D'Amboise ["He Makes Me Feel Like Dancing" video], 1983; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Off-air recording of Academy Award won by Jacques D'Amboise documentary "He Makes Me Feel Like Dancing," followed by documentary itself.
    - Dancing Up A Storm. The Story of NDI's 1st International Residency: Israel 1997. With Jacques D'Amboise [note from D'Amboise & press release enclosed], 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 50, Folder 6)
      documentary about Jacques D'Amboise teaching children in Israel, directed by Amir Gera.
  - Ron Davis (Box 177, Folder 3)
    Artist from Sebastopol, California.
    Davis, Ron
  - Margaret De Patta, Eugene Bielawski, Martha Bielawski (Box 177, Folder 4)
    De Patta was a pioneering modernist jewelsmith in San Francisco who traded work with Ruth. De Patta was an early member of the Metal Arts Guild along with Merry Renk. She took her life in 1964, and there is very little correspondence from her here. Her husband and his second wife wrote a few letters later.
    De Patta, Margaret; Bielawski, Eugene
  - Onno and Aty De Ruyter (Box 177, Folder 5)
    Onno De Ruyter was one of the founders of S.F. Art Foundry, which did alot of casting for Ruth, including the Ghirardelli Fountain.
    Ruyter, Onno de; Ruyter, Aty de
  - Eleanor Dickinson (Box 177, Folder 6)
    San Francisco painter, graphic artist and teacher. Active in Artists Equity Association with Ruth.
    The Smithsonian Archives of American Art holds the Eleanor Dickinson papers: http://www.aaa.si.edu/collections/eleanor-dickinson-papers-6477
    Dickinson, Eleanor
  - Shoshana Dubiner (Box 177, Folder 7)
    CETA/Alvarado artist-in-residence in the 1970s.
    Shoshanah
  - Anne Smith Easley (Box 177, Folder 8)
    Artist, daughter of Page and Eloise Smith.
    Easley, Anne
  - Joe Ehreth (Box 177, Folder 9)
    Artist, photographer, and cinematographer who worked with the Halprins.
    Ehreth, Joe
  - D-E (Box 177, Folder 10)
    Chantal DeCleve; Kenneth Derby; Verity Diefauf; Judy Dunworth; Maurice English; Harold Ehrensperger; Eunice Elton; Bob Ernstthal; Lisa Esherick; Connor Everts
  - Valerie Ferrier (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Later Valerie Jacobs. Graphic designer, printer, Alvarado artist-in-residence. Designed Japanese Tea Garden book that Ruth illustrated.
    Jacobs, Valerie Ferrier
  - Gordon Onslow Ford (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Bay Area post-Surrealist painter who once owned a Sausalito houseboat with Jean Varda. Contains exhibition notices, little or no correspondence.
    Onslow-Ford, Gordon
  - Buckminster and Anne Fuller
    Stanford holds extensive collections on Fuller, including the R. Buckminster Fuller Papers (M1090): http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf109n9832. Fuller's Dymaxion Chronofile contains a good deal of correspondence with Asawa.
    Canonical 20th century thinker and polymath R. Buckminster Fuller needs little introduction. Ruth and Albert met Bucky and Anne Fuller at Black Mountain College in 1948. Both studied with Fuller. Albert took part in the famous "supine dome" episode, and Ruth cut his hair (she made extra money barbering) and Fuller in turn made her a barber pole from venetian blinds. Their enduring friendship is reflected in the great deal of correspondence present, especially from Anne. As with the Albers, Asawa respectfully addresses them as Mr. and Mrs. Fuller; he often calls her Dearest Ruth.
    In one of Fuller's reference letters for an Asawa Guggenheim application, he is quite generous with his praise: "I state, without hesitation or reserve, that I consider Ruth Asawa to be the most gifted, productive and originally inspired artist that I have ever known personally." She also received the first Dymaxion Award for Artist-Scientist in 1966.
    Ruth credited him for her educational direction: "He inspired me to work with young children. When I asked him what should I do in the schools, he said 'Give every kindergarten child a PhD! Create an environment and learning will take place. Work directly with the children.' I took his advice."
    Asawa cast Fuller’s hands and face in 1966, and later sculpted a large bust of his head. She also attended many lectures, some of which she arranged, and made sketches and notes. See the Calendars and Planners series for these.
    Asawa was on the board of the Buckminster Fuller Institute for one year following Fuller's death in 1983, and there is correspondence, newsletters, catalogs and other material from this time.
    Also of note are photographs, audio recordings of lectures, and videotaped news segments on the discovery of "Buckyballs." More material related to Fuller can be found in the Black Mountain College series and elsewhere in the collection.
    Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster); Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster); Fuller, Anne Hewlett; Fuller, Anne Hewlett
    - chronological files
      - undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1949-1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1996-2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 2006-2013 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - articles and publications, 1946-2008 (Box 11, Folders 1-5)
    - Snyders (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with Fuller’s daughter Allegra Fuller Snyder and her husband Robert Snyder, as well as some from their children Jaime Snyder and Alexandra Snyder. The majority concerns Robert Snyder's "On Forms and Growth" documentary on Asawa, which was partially funded by Fuller.
      Snyder, Allegra Fuller; Snyder, Jaime; Snyder, Robert
    - Geo-Globes (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Asawa’s son Xavier (and later Adam) built and sold Fuller-designed spherical polyurethane lamp shades (referred to as "Geo-Globes" or "Geodesic Globes").
    - oversize